[SOUND]. So there's a nice connection between these
在这些OLAP数据立方操作和
OLAP data cube operations and
我们见到的各种Infovis操作之间
various Infovis operations that we've looked at,
有很好的联系
for example in Shneiderman's mantra.
比如在Shneiderman的准则中
A common data cube operation is slicing.
一个常见的数据立方 操作是切片
And that's basically taking a summarized axis or
这基本上就是 选取一个完整的坐标轴
some full axis and looking at a specific value along that axis.
或者一个概括后的坐标轴 然后跟着坐标轴观察特定的值
So, for example, this could be the location axis,
例如 这个可以是 表示地址的坐标轴
and this data cube represents all of your data across all the locations.
这个数据立方表示了 所有地址的数据
You can pick a particular location and then start to look at just the data for
你可以选取一个特定地址 然后只看这个地址的数据
that particular location, that slicing.
只看着那个切片
And we do that in Infovis just by filtering value along that dimension.
在Infovis里 我们可以通过 筛选该维度的数据来实现
Similarly dicing, if we have the full data cube representing all of the ranges,
与之相似的还有切块操作 若有表示所有区间的数据立方
we can limit those ranges by dicing, by looking at sub cubes of the data cube.
我们可以通过切块以限制区间 只观察某个子块
And we do that in Infovis by setting up filter ranges instead of ordinal or
在Infovis中可以用区间筛选 而非类别量筛选来实现
nominal filter values, or individual values, we have a range of values.
也可以通过独立变量 我们有很多变量
And if those values correspond to the coordinates used for plotting,
如果这些量和图中的坐标轴对应
then we do the same thing where we zoom a plot area in Infovis.
那么这就相当于观察 Infovis图中放大后的一个区域
So slicing could reduce the dimension of the data cube.
所以切片可以减少数据立方的维度
We can also aggregate to reduce
我们也可以通过聚合来 减少数据立方的维度
And so if we sum along, or find some other aggregation measure in average across one
如果沿一个方向求和 或者用其他聚合手法
of the dimensions, then that reduces the dimensionality of the data cube,
沿一个维度求均值 那么就能减少数据立方的维度
makes it easier to see the value.
让观察数据变得更容易
That's the standard aggregation operation.
有一个标准聚合操作
And then there is also disaggregation, and
还有去聚合操作
when we aggregate the data in data cube terminology we call that a roll-up.
以及对数据立方做聚合时 有一个术语叫上卷
We're rolling up all the values
我们把值向上卷起
into average values or
变成平均值
aggregate values here.
或者聚合后的值
If we do the opposite operation that's called a drill down,
它的逆操作叫做下钻
we drill down into the details.
我们向下钻入细节
So we're disaggregating.
也就是去聚合
We're taking our average values here and expanding them out to the data.
选择这里的平均值 然后把它们扩展到数据
And we see this all the time when we zoom on fields or
当我们在数据区中缩放 或在Tableau里
get details on demand in Tableau.
根据需求选择细节时 会常常见到它们
It's when we start dragging fields on the shelves in order to expand,
也就是我们拖动架子上的区段来扩展它们了
based on the dimensions associated with those fields.
即基于这些数据区段的维度
And finally the pivot term, and this is where pivot table
最后还有轴转（Pivot） 数据透视表（Pivot Table） 因此得名
gets the term pivot from, is basically a rotation of the data cube.
它相当于对数据立方的旋转
You're changing which faces your looking at, you're swapping axes.
你可改变观看立方体哪一面 也就是在交换坐标轴
So you're changing the role of a dimension on a particular visualization of the data.
这样你就是在数据可视化 的视图中改变一个维度的角色
We do that simply by field selection.
我们可以简单地 用场景选取来达成
In Tableau, we're just dragging fields around to see
在Tableau中我们可以 把场景拖来拖去
what we're looking at at any given instance.
以显示任意场合中 我们所看到的东西
We can show, for example, how all of the data cube operations on a database,
我们也可以显示 比如 立方操作在数据库中是怎样的
in this case the data cube of the world bank indicators,
这个例子是世界银行指数 的数据立方
how all of our data cube operations can be implemented
我们的数据立方操作 是怎样通过信息可视化工具来实现
using an information visualization tool, in this case, Tableau.
本例中的工具即是Tableau
So I'm displaying here a plot of infant mortality over life expectancy,
这样就显示出一张婴儿死亡率 与预期寿命的关系图
and infant mortality is measured over deaths per 1,000 children,
婴儿死亡率是根据每1000个 儿童中的死亡数确定的
and so you want a lower infant mortality.
你会希望婴儿死亡率低一些
And this is the the infant mortality rate and
这是婴儿死亡率和 平均预期寿命
the life expectancy average over the dimensions of our dataset, basically time.
在数据集合中每个维度的均值 基本上是时间维度的均值
Our dataset is measures every year over ten years, and then by country.
我们的数据集是在十年间 每年 每个国家测量一次
It's being averaged over every country in the world.
对全世界每个国家 都取了均值
And so we can look at the different data cube operations we can apply to this
这样我们来看可以在这里使用的 不同的数据立方操作
data cube, in our presentation, for example, slicing.
例如在本演示中的切片操作
So if I take this dataset and I expand it,
如果我拿到这个数据集 并且扩展它
disaggregate it by region, we'll assign region the color, I get the continents.
按照地区来去聚合 把地区上色后 就得到按各大洲的分布
Basically I desegregate by continent.
基本上就是按大洲来去聚合
And now we can see how each of the continents is doing.
这样我们就可以看出 每个大洲的情况
I can slice the dataset by looking at, basically,
我还可以通过 关注于一个数据点
one data point and I can keep only that data point.
并且只保留那个点的方式 来对数据集切片
That creates a filter operation
这样就产生了一种筛选操作
in our information tool that's doing the slice operation.
在我们的工具里 这也是切片操作
We've sliced by a continent and
我们按照大洲来切片
that continent represents a collection of countries, and so
大洲表示国家的集合
that operation is actually also performed, the dice operation.
这样这个操作实际做的是 切块操作
And by basically focusing on a range of items, a sub cube, and so
关注一个区间内的数据 比如一个子立方
we can see what countries are represented by bringing over countries.
这样可以通过查询其他国家 来看国家是如何表示的
And so if I disaggregate by country, now these averages are basically over time.
如果按照国家来去聚合 那么平均值就是对时间的平均
But each country represents an average over time of the infant mortality and and
每个国家都代表了 欧洲国家婴儿死亡率和预期寿命
life expectancy of the countries in Europe.
对时间的平均值
And so I've diced our dataset into just the European portion.
这样就把数据集切块成 只有欧洲的部分
And then we can roll these back up.
然后就可以把它们上卷
If you want to do a roll-up, we're going to simplify,
如果要做上卷
we're going to aggregate again.
我们只要重新进行聚合即可
And so for example, I can get rid of the country and
所以例如 我可以不看国家数据
just look at Europe.
只看欧洲
And that's sort of a roll-up of all that data back into a summary view.
这就是把所有数据 上卷回概括视图
So we're averaging over all the countries in Europe for that data point.
也就是在这个数据点上 我们对欧洲的所有国家求均值
And then we can remove the dice and slice operation and
然后也可以去除这个切块以及切片操作
just look at the original dataset.
只看原始数据集
Now we might want to drill down into some of the details of this.
现在我们可能想要下钻 到其中的一些细节
By drilling down, we're doing the opposite of a roll-up.
下钻和上卷相反
Instead of aggregating by averaging or
它不是通过取平均 或者求和来聚合
summing, we're going to disaggregate to drill down into the details.
而是要去聚合以后钻研细节
We've already drilled down into the regions,
我们已经深入到地区了
we can also drill down into the date.
还可以下钻到日期
Each one of these dots represents an average over ten years, for
这里每个点代表了 十年间
each of these continents.
每个大洲的平均
So I can disaggregate to drill down into the performance
我可以通过拖放到年份一栏 来下钻到
per year by just dragging into year here.
每一年的表现
We can use a line plot to look at this better and you can see
可以用折线图来更好地观察 你可以看到
the trends that each of these continents is basically improving over each year.
每个大洲的趋势 基本上是逐年上升的
2005, 6, 7, 2009.
2005 2006 2007 2009
Each one of these continents is improving its life expectancy.
每个大洲的预期寿命 都在提升
Increasing its life expectancy, decreasing its infant mortality.
提升预期寿命 降低婴儿死亡率
And so we can drill down even further by differentiating
还可以再向下钻
each of these continents by its individual countries.
深入到每个大洲的各个国家来
And we get a plot like this, and so we've drilled down into finer details for
我们就可以得到这张图 这样就深入到
each country in each continent.
每个大洲每个国家的细节
And we can see how each individual country is performing,
可以看到各个国家的表现
as it tries to reduce its infant mortality and increase its life expectancy.
它们都试图降低婴儿死亡率 提高预期寿命
And then finally there's the pivot operation,
最后还有旋转操作
if I go back to the continent view.
如果回到大洲视图
Pivot operation is basically a rotation of the data cube.
旋转操作基本上是 对数据立方的旋转
We're differentiating by region here, by continent here,
我们在这里根据大洲 根据地区来分类
the performance of infant mortality versus life expectancy.
分区看婴儿死亡率和预期寿命 之间的表现
I can cycle fields in Tableau and that basically performs a rotation.
可以连续使用Tableau中的场景 这相当于旋转
Now I'm coloring by year and then by region,
现在我根据年份着色 然后根据地区着色
so I've just cycled those fields.
所以我循环使用了这些场景
And we can continue to cycle the fields and
我们还能继续重复这样的操作
see different views of our data based
从而根据数据立方的 不同旋转方位
on different rotations of the data cube.
看数据集的不同视图
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community